let's take a look at the one-dimensional
wave equation for an electric field the
function we're looking for is the
electric field e this depends on the
position X and on the time T since the
function depends on two variables and
their derivatives appear in the equation
it is a partial differential equation
here we make a product onzas for the
searched solution e e is equal to R * U
we assume that this solution e e can be
split into a product of two functions
that we call r and u one function R
depends only on X and the other function
U depends only on T in the wave equation
we have a second derivative of e with
respect to location X and a second
derivative with respect to time T
differentiating the product on that with
respect to X yields U * the second
derivative of r with respect to X Since
U is independent of X and thus acts like
a
constant in contrast in the derivative
of the product with respect to time T
the function R acts like a constant
because it does not depend on T the goal
now is to separate everything that
depends on X from what depends on T for
this we divide this equation by R *
U
thus we have achieved that everything
that depends on X is on the left side
and everything that depends on T is on
the right side if you manage to separate
a partial differential equation this way
then the separation unz was successful
now we can vary X on the left side
without changing the right side because
there is no X on the right side the same
is true for the time T if we vary the
time on the the right side the left side
remains unchanged because there is no
time T thus both sides must be constant
so let us set the left side and the
right side equal to a constant
K thus we have transformed a partial
differential equation into two ordinary
differential equations and the good
thing is that the two differential
equations are not coupled that means you
can solve them independently and then
multiply the solutions like in the
product onz to get the general solution
for the partial differential
equation you can solve the two ordinary
differential equations with the
exponential UNS you learned
before